montgomerycollege.edu 2019-10-28

# Privacy Statement | Montgomery College, Maryland

Montgomery College provides access to various services, activities and information online in a manner that respects and protects your individual privacy. This statement describes our information-collection practices and explains how we use and protect your personal data.  This Privacy Statement describes our practices in connection with data that we collect: 

  * Through our Montgomery College (MC) website and affiliated pages where you may access this this Privacy Statement (the “ **Websites** ”), 
  * through the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “ **Apps** ”), 
  * through our social media pages and applications made available by us for use on or through computers or moble devices (collectively, our “ **Social Media Pages** ”) 
  * through HTML-formatted email messages that we send to you that link to this Privacy Statement 
  * through offline activities as detailed in this Statement

## Personal Information we collect and process:

When you access or use the Websites, Apps or Social media Pages, we may collect and process the following types of information from you: 

“ **Personal Information** ” is any information that we can reasonably use to identify you. If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), Personal Information includes all Personal Data as defined under EEA laws.  If you are an EEA Data Subject, you may have additional rights as delineated in our GDPR Interim Statement. 

Personal Information we collect and process Purpose of Processing | Categories of Personal Information | Legal Basis  
---|---|---  
**Course Registration:**   To support course registration  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID, contact information, educational history | _Legitimate Interest_ : Personal Information collected for matriculated students, staff, faculty and members of the public, as appropriate for the course, to register in courses or classes   
**Disability Support Services** | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID, contact information, educational history | _Legitimate Interest_ : Personal Information collected for students, as appropriate for the determination of disability support services for s student    
**Online Training:**   To provide online training and educational programs  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID, contact information, demographic information | _Legitimate Interest_ : To facilitate provision of on-line education courses to matriculated students, staff, faculty and members of the public, as appropriate for the course   
**Wellness Programs** :  To enroll in wellness programs  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID | _Legitimate Interest_ : For eligible individuals interested in participating in a variety of wellness programs, courses, activities, facilitate enrollment and communications about the programs  
 _Contract_ : If there is a contract for participation in wellness programs, Personal Information is processed pursuant to that contract   
**Employment Applications** :  To process employment applications  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID (if available), demographic information, resumes | _Legitimate Interest_ : For individuals interested in employment opportunities, processing applications   
**Visa Applications** :  To process visa applications  | Name, demographic information, financial information, passport number | _Legal Requirements_  
**Advancement** :  To receive donations  | Name, contact information, payment information | _Legitimate Interest_ : To collect and process donations/gifts and donor information   
**Events:**   To purchase tickets to events  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID (if available), contact information, payment information | _Contract_ : To process ticket payment for a variety of events   
**Parking Permits:**   To purchase parking passes and permits  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID, contact information, payment information | _Contract_ : To facilitate payments for parking passes and permits   
**IT Service Desk:**   To submit requests for services (e.g., IT Service Desk)  | Name, Montgomery College Unique ID, contact information |    
  
## Why is the information collected by the montgomerycollege.edu website?

Montgomery College collects website visitor information to: best serve audiences by optimizing and personalizing visitor experiences in both digital and physical spaces, manage a visitor relationship with the university, foster/promote further communications, gauge communication effectiveness, gain insights into user behavior and preferences, track interests, identify errors and issues, and conduct market research. 

## Students and Consent 

When you apply with us and later register as a student, you give us consent to process personal data about you as necessary for the proper administration of your student relationship with the College.  That process limits how your personal data will be shared.  Complete information on the handling of student records in accordance with FERPA may be found in the College's [Student Cumulative Records](https://cms.montgomerycollege.edu/EDU/Verified_-_Policies_and_Procedures/PDF_Versions/41003_Student_Cumulative_Records/) policy. Student with questions can call the Montgomery College Response Center at 240-567-5000. 

## Minors/Children

The College Websites, Apps or Social Media are not directed to children under the age of thirteen (13).    We do not sell products or services intended for purchase by children under the age of 13, nor do we knowingly collect or store any personal information/data, even in aggregate, provided by children under the age of 13. 

## Interest-Based Advertisements

Some of our Sites engage in online interest-based advertising to enhance your experience and show you advertisements that might interest you. Like many organizations, we and our advertising partners display tailored interest-based advertising using information you make available to us when you interact with our Sites.  Interest-based ads, also sometimes referred to as personalized or targeted ads, are displayed to you based on information from activities such as searching on our Sites or visiting websites that contain our content or ads. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers. 

Visit [Your Ad Choices](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) or [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) to learn more about interest-based ads or to opt-out of receiving third-party interest based ads. Please note that if you opt out of interest-based advertising, you will still see advertisements – they will just not be tailored to your interests.  Also note that deleting browser cookies can remove the cookie preferences you have made, so you may need to opt-out again in the future. 

## Cookies

For more information about cookies review the Cookie Notice of Montgomery College.

## Google Analytics

In some instances, we may use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the websites and report on activities and trends.  This service may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. Learn more about [Google’s practices](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites), and opt out of them by [downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

## Marketing

Personal Information you submit through our Sites, such as your name, address and other contact information, may be collected by Montgomery College for internal marketing and development purposes as well as to respond to your inquiry, complete a transaction for you, or fulfill other forms of customer service. You can choose not to receive marketing from us by “unsubscribing” using the instructions in any marketing email you receive from us. 

## Third Parties Websites

Montgomery College may contract and partner with external third-parties to place ads on websites not affiliated with Montgomery College. These non-affiliated sites may send and share visitor information and browsing behavior, collected in accordance with their own privacy policies, with Montgomery College. These third-party websites may also display advertisements to previous visitors of the Montgomery College site. 

## Sharing your Personal Information

We share your information internally at Montgomery College to facilitate and manage the purposes listed above. This includes third parties whom Montgomery College engages to process your Personal Information on our behalf for the purposes stated above, such as vendors who help Montgomery College with our marketing, application processing, and web hosting. Montgomery College may also share your personal data with government and law enforcement agencies or regulators to 1) comply with a legal process, subpoena, order or other legal or regulatory requirement applicable to us; 2) enforce our terms of use or other policies; or 3) pursue available legal remedies or defend against legal claims. Other third parties as you may so request as permitted by this and other Montgomery College policies and applicable laws and regulations. Montgomery College will not sell any personal information to third parties for their use in direct marketing, advertising, or promotion of their products or services. 

## Non-personally identifiable information we collect and process

Standard, non-personally identifiable internet log information such as browser type and navigation to various parts of the Sites, in an aggregated form, is collected for analytical purposes to improve the browsing experience of our Sites, update relevant content and improve the overall design. 

## Document Retention

We keep your Personal Information for as long as needed to fulfill the particular purpose for which it was collected. We may also retain your records if legally required or to fulfill a legitimate interest. 

## Updates to Privacy Statement

Montgomery College reserves the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time. Your continued use of the Sites after any change in this Privacy Statement will constitute your acceptance of such change. 

## Contact Information

For more information on how we collect and process your Personal Information, or if you have any complaints please contact [privacy@montgomerycollege.edu](mailto:privacy@montgomerycollege.edu). 

## Effective Date

The effective date of this Statement is May 25, 2018.
